Speaker: Meet Tom.
Like everyone, Tom likes to get a good night’s sleep.
And like us all, Tom has about five separate dreams every night.
These dreams can last between fifteen and forty minutes.
According to experts, our dreams tell us who we are,
what we need, and what we believe in,
so, for Tom and for everyone else, here is a guide to the most common dreams and their meanings.
Dream one: Somebody is running after you.
If you have this dream, it means something is worrying you in real life.
Something like a difficult decision or a difficult situation with a friend or a colleague.
People often have this dream again and again until they make the decision
or deal with the situation that is worrying them.
Dream two: You can’t find something you need.
Dreaming about losing something and trying to find it again is surprisingly common.
It usually means that you’re worried about something stressful that you need to do soon,
like going on a long journey or giving a talk in public.
In these situations, people sometimes dream about losing their passport or tickets,
or losing their notes or memory stick.
Dream three: You’re unprepared for an exam.
This dream is common for young adults or children who are under stress, and it can feel very real –
sometimes you can wake up sure that you’ve just failed an important exam or test.
If you’re not doing any exams in real life,
this dream could mean that you don’t have enough confidence in your ability to do something.
Dream four: You’re flying or falling.
Another very common dream is the flying dream.
Sometimes people dream that they are in control.
If you feel in control, it means that your life is successful –
perhaps you’ve just passed an important exam, or your boss has given you a promotion.
But usually, people dream that they’re out of control and falling.
This means the opposite – your life isn’t going well,
and you’re worried about what’s going to happen in the future.
Dream five: You’re under water.
If you dream that you’re under water,
but you’re feeling happy and comfortable and you can still breathe,
it could mean you have very strong feelings for someone.
You’re probably in love!
Sometimes dreams come true, but more often, they don’t!
Sweet dreams!